Miscellaneous Memorabilia Collection, 1850s-2004
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Miscellaneous memorabilia collection
1850s-2004
MS 441
10 boxes (5.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Includes postcards of women and historic sites pertaining to women, unidentified photographs of women and families, political buttons, and posters.
The Miscellaneous Memorabilia Collection contains postcards of women and historic sites pertaining to women; photographs and other images, mostly unidentified, of women and families; and numerous political buttons reflecting the opinions of various types of activism, mostly feminism. Received from various donors, the postcard collection is eclectic in that it contains images of women who represent a range of social callings and political persuasions from Susan B. Anthony and Harriet Beecher Stowe, to Marilyn Monroe, Cleopatra, and Miss America. The photographs include portraits, snapshots, and postcards of women and families organized by decades. Also included are 31 commemorative portrait medallions of famous women, issued from 1968 to 1979 by the Societe Commemorative de Femmes Celebres, plus newsletters and related documents, as well as a few posters from the March for Women's Lives in Washington, DC, April 2004.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to collection are expected.
History of the Collection
Materials in this subject collection were either purchased or given to the Sophia Smith Collection by various donors.
Search Terms
Women--History--Pictorial works; Photography of women--History--Sources; Postcards--United States--History--20th century-- Sources; Feminism--History--Collectibles
APPENDIX: List of postcards
Louisa May Alcott
Priscilla Alden
Miss America
Susan B. Anthony
Clara Barton
Rebecca and Abigail Bates
Sarah Bernhardt
Belle Boyd
Lizzie Borden
Audrey and Elsie Brinkley
Nancy Brown
Pearl Buck
Edith Cavell
Cleopatra
Katherine Cornell
Elizabeth Cushman
Zena Dare
Diana Darrell
Dionne quints
Dorothy Dix
Hannah Duston
Amelia Earhart
Mary Baker Eddy
Evangeline
Frances Fairchild (Bryant)
Mrs. John Lowell Gardner
Hampton Beach Memorial
Ann Hathaway
Margaret Haugery
Almira and Georgiana Hillman
Lady Caroline Howard
Helen Hunt Jackson
Mary Jamison
Anna M. Jarvis
Joanne of Arc
Helen Keller
Gertrude Lawrence
Annie Allegra Longfellow
Caroline Lowe
Juliette Gordon Lowe
Mary Lyon
Jane McCrae
Madonna of the trail monuments
Maria Mitchell
Margaret Mitchell
Marilyn Monroe
Lucy Maude Montgomery
Grandma Moses
Lucretia Mott
Lillian Nordica
Rebecca Nurse
Ocean Born Mary House
Elizabeth Pabodie
Alice Freeman Palmer
Persia
Gabrielle Petit
Mary Pickford
Pilgrim maiden/mother
Pioneer women monuments
Pocahontas
Emily Post
Ramona
Alice Roosevelt
Betsy Ross
Lillian Russell
Ann Rutledge
Sakajawea
Deborah Sampson
Mary E. Schenley
Mary Shaw
Frances Slocum
Elizabeth Foster (Mother Goose)
Margaret Chase Smith
Barbara Fritchie
Elizabeth Cady Stanton
Statue of Liberty
Lucy Stone
Harriet Beecher Stowe
Tahitian Dancer
Shirley Temple (Black)
Nyla Thompson
Joanna Troutmann
United Daughters of the Confederacy
Jennie Wade
Mrs. Humphrey Ward
Mary (Polly) Warner
Peregrine White
Mrs. Wiggs
Ella Wheeler Wilcox
Frances Willard
Mrs. Willoughby
- Postcards of women and historic sites related to women (Box 1)
  [See appendix]
- Pamphlets: women's history sites and tours (Box 1A)
- Photographs and other images of women and families1860s-1950s (Box 2)
- Political buttons (Box 3-4A)
  [See accession lists and notes in finding aid folder.]
- 31 commemorative portrait medallions issued by the Societe de Commemorative de Femmes Celebres, newsletters and related documents1968-2004 (Box 5)
- Photograph (photocopy) and publications1976, undated (Box 5)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Mobilize for Women's Lives march ribbon sash, Lincoln Memorial, Washington, D.C.1989 November 12 (Box 6)
  - March for Women's Lives, D.C.: posters, fliers, and memorabilia2004 April 25 (Box 6)
    [See list in finding aid folder.]
  - Lavendar Menace t-shirt; scarf and tote bag made from t-shirts1970s (Box 7)
  - Images featuring women clipped from Ballou's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion, Harper's Weekly, The Illustrated London News, Illustrated Times1855-1875 (Box 8)
  - Posters (5): March for Women's Lives, D.C., April 2004 (Map-case Flat file)